BASHAYER SAUD BIN SARAAN



CONTACT

+966557798270

Br.1999q@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bashayer-saraan

Saudi Arabia, Riyadh

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java, HTML, CSS, C++,XML
- Troubleshooting & proplem solving
- Software Installation
- Network Configuration
- Technical Support
- Communication & Excellent interpersonal
- Creative Thinking Skills
- Front-End & Back-End Development

EDUCATION

Diploma of InformationTechnology 2017-2019

Princess Nora Bint Abdulrahman University with GPA 4.25

Professional Certification

- ITIL 4 2022
- Saudi Council of Engineers Accreditation 2021

Arabic

English



LANGUAGES

SUMMARY

Information Technology Specialist with 3+ years of expericence in major companies, my objective is to seek an opportunity within an organization, where I could demonstrate my current capabilities and expand it further. Also to gain more knowledge and experience.

My aim is to strive for the best, deliver better services the organization on all level, learn and improve existing knowledge, skills, ability.

I have unlimited ambitious to be part of our National 2030 vision journey by carrying out my positive motivation and make markable achievements in my life.

On personal perspective I'm always flexible, smooth and having energy which will allow me to do multiple different tasks and creat an Initiative ideas and finding/ obtaining solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Service Desk Specialist

Tahakom, Technology Investment affiliated company

July2021-Oct2022

- Receive and analyze internal and external users requests and complains.
- Solve and coach the users on frontend solvable issues.
- Manage network servers and technology tools.
- Ensure security through access controls, backups and firewalls.
- Raise and escalate any general issues and follow-up resolution.
- · Comply with defined processes and update tickets within SLA.
- Add, delete, or update user account information, reset passwords, etc.
- Analyse system records and identify potential problems with computer systems.
- Set up and troubleshoot VPN issues.
- Mange active directory, Exchange server and office 365.

Key achievement

- · Maintained 99% satisfaction rating in monthly end-user scoring through applied interpersonal skills and providing fast solutions.
- Became a trusted resource through high-level problem-solving skills. Solved customer issues with 15% more success than the company average.
- Handled trouble tickets 25% faster than other desktop support engineers.
- Create all Knowledges in Knowledge transfer platform related to Service Desk.
- · Over achieved monthly KPI of closing end user requests/issues during all my employment period.

IT Support Engineer

Mar2020-June2021

Ericsson, project with Mobily operation center

- Receive and analyze external users requests and complains related to billing, services and complains.
- Assign the issues in ticket to the right team and follow-up resolution.
- Stay up to with system information, changes and updates.
- Performing impact analysis and gap analysis.
- Raise and escalate issues as per Escalation Matrix.

Feb 2019- May 2019

IT Support Internshipt

Tatweer Education Holding Company

- Setting up and installing new/old computers, Printers, network equipment, IP telephones, and software.
- Installing and configuring operating systems.
- Monitor CPU, memory and hard disk utilization, Monitor the event viewer and generating reports.
- Analyze problems with the service and resolve the issues.
- · Network Administration/ Security / Support.
- Resolving all issues coworkers have with their ITsystems and software.
- Educating coworkers about network security and best practices for computer usage.